Guide to the African Student Organizations at Stanford Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
African student organizations at Stanford collection
1982-2010
SC0985
Stanford African Students Association.
1.5 Linear feet
Collection includes event materials, newsletters, publications, correspondence, and other records, primarily from the Stanford African Students Association, 1989-2010; other organizations include Association of Stanford Southern Africans, Stanford Ethiopian and Eritrean Students Association, and Stanford Nigerian Students Association. Also included are videorecordings (VHS) from Africa Week, sponsored by the Stanford African Students Association, 1996 and 1997.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes event materials, newsletters, publications, correspondence, and other records, primarily from the Stanford African Students Association, 1989-2010; other organizations include Association of Stanford Southern Africans, Stanford Ethiopian and Eritrean Students Association, and Stanford Nigerian Students Association. Also included are videorecordings (VHS) from Africa Week, sponsored by the Stanford African Students Association, 1996 and 1997.
Access Terms
African students--California.; Students, Foreign--California.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Africa Week [sponsored by Stanford African Students Association], organizational materials, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Africa Week, event schedule, list of committees, programs, flyers, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Africa Week, schedule of events, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Africa Week, program and organizational materials, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Africa Week, African Culture Night program, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africa Week, event schedule and loose photos, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Africa Week, event schedule 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa Week, event program, flyer, budget, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Africa Week, event schedule, flyer, dance program, organizational materials, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Africa Week, event schedule flyer, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Africa Week, event schedule posters and other materials, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Africa Week, event schedule posters and flyers, Stanford Daily coverage, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Africa Week flyer 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Africa Week flyers 2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mawazo (SASA newsletter), sales and receipt forms (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mawazo, correspondence and other records (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mawazo, miscellaneous materials (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - SASA correspondence, 1989 Annual Report, and other records, 1986-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Stanford student publications: IASA Resume Book [compiled by SASA]; Soul Sistah, June 2004; The Black Community Sourcebook 1991[published by the Black Community Services Center at Stanford] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Other student publications: Future 2002 Black Graduations Issue [West coast Black Student Network]; Outlook, The Harvard/Radcliffe Freshman Black Table Annual Journal 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SASA Photograph album Africa Week 2000 (Box 2, Folder nf)
  - Clippings, 1997-2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - An Africanist Directory, compiled by Ernest J. Valenzuela, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Grenada: Reagan’s propaganda victory; British and American press coverage [Produced by SCAAN – Stanford central America Action Network] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Academic events, 1984, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cultural and political events (mostly flyers) 1983-2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Association of Stanford Southern Africans, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Ethiopian and Eritrean Students Association [or the Stanford Eritrean and Ethiopian Students Association], 2004-2010 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Nigerian Students Association, 1998-2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Africa Business Forum, program for “Fortune at the Bottom of the African Pyramid,” May 2010 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Highlights of the Third African-African American Summit: Dakar, Senegal, May 1-6, 1995, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
- Videotapes
  - Mrs. Berhane Ras-Work. Keynote Speaker, Africa Week 1996. “Africa 2020”, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: Dr. Celestin Monga “Prospects for Democracy in Africa,” Africa Week 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: African Drumming Ceremony by Oriki Theater, Africa Week 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: [Student panel] “Toward a Vision of Africa,” Africa Week 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: panel discussion: Africans on Research in Africa, a Research Manifesto. Africa Week 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: Cultural Celebration, April 25. Africa Week, 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa 2020: Traditional Africa Night, cultural performances. Africa Week, 1996, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Hafsat Abiola. Keynote Speaker, Africa Week 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa Table. Student panel on African Entrepreneurship. Africa Week 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Africa Night, April 26. Africa Week 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Culture Night, April 24. Africa Week 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
General note
Stanford African Students Association T-shirt and trophy can be found in the Stanford Archives Museum Collection under the call number AM 2010-004.